AYOTUNDE AYOOLA

23, Shitu Animashaun, Gbagada Phase 2 Estate, Lagos-Nigeria • +234 (0) 7033980855

Email: ayotundeayoola005@gmail.com · LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ayotundeayoola-27708a89/

I am a Technology and Solutions Architect with over a decade work experience in Software Engineering, Enterprise Applications Development, DevOps Practices, Functional/Non-Functional Consulting in technological areas that cut across development, implementation, training, management, and Support. I have strong knowledge in management and practical engagements in various tech-ecosystem ranging from Enterprise, Bespoke systems, and Core-Apps modelling, this then help span across engagement with solutions such as Microsoft Power Platform, SharePoint, Dynamics 365 CRM and Techno-Functionalities, Azure DevOps, Microsoft 365 Solutions, AWS, GCP, SAP SuccessFactors, S4Hana, Salesforce, CMS, and IT Management.

I am also a Microsoft MVP in Business Applications, MCP (Microsoft Certified Professional) and a Microsoft Certified Trainer with outstanding management, technical, communication and presentation skills. I have a great team and collaboration ability which is motivated by learning, development, and application innovation practices to always bring about digital transformation.

EXPERIENCE

08/2014 - PRESENT (STARTED AS FREELANCE CONSULTANT FOR 7 YEARS, NOW WORKS FULL-TIME FOR THE COMPANY)

PRINCIPAL CONSULTANT (HEAD OF TECHNOLOGY) – STRINGIFY TS.

- Microsoft Power Platform (Development, Support and Trainings)
- Microsoft Dynamics CRM (Development, Support and Trainings)
- Azure Cloud/DevOps Engineer
- Software Development
- Technology Training (Virtual, On-site and Tutorials), (YouTube Channel: Ayotunde Ayoola)

Projects include: https://feastofesther.orq, https://lifebeyondclass.com

TECHNOLOGY CONSULTING | (IMPLEMENTATION/TRAINING)

I have been involved in various consulting-based project implementation for various organizations in various technological areas from management to development and training. Industries I have worked with span through Technology Partners, Finance, Insurance, Audit, NGOs, Government, and a host other of which some are large enterprise, MSMEs and Start-Ups.

Area of Consult and Engagement:

- Digital Transformation for Organizations
- Business Transformation with technology
- Microsoft Dynamics CRM (Development, Support and Trainings)
- Microsoft Power Platform (Development, Support and Trainings) 2018 till present
- Azure and SharePoint (Development, Support and Trainings)
- Microsoft 365 (Development, Support and Trainings)
- Software Development (c#, Laravel, DevOps and Project Management)
- Quality Assurance and Penetration Testing.
- SAP Implementations and Trainings
- Cloud Infrastructure Consult (Azure, AWS, GCP, Digital Ocean and public hosted platforms)

03/2022 - 06/2022

TECHNICAL LEAD (SOLUTIONS ARCHITECT, SME) | DYNAMICS CRM & POWER PLATFORM – CLOUD SOLUTIONS PARTNER (ROMANIA)

- Implementation of Dynamics CRM for an International NGO
- Dynamics CRM Implementation for internal use (Modules: Sales, Customer Service and PSA)
- Dynamics CRM Field Service Implementation and Support
- Power Platform Development with (Power Apps (Model-Driven Apps, Portal, and Canvas App), Power Automate, RPA, Power BI, and Power Virtual Agents.
- Power Platform Extensibility (Custom controls and client scripting creation, PCF Controls, Custom connectors, Plugins and Azure Functions with JavaScript (TypeScript), C# ASP.Net, XrmTools and Other Plugin Deployment tools).
- Functional Consulting and Solution Architecting (Leveraging on skills of Project Governance, ALM, Presales, Design conceptualization, DevOps for Project Management and Solution Management)
- User Adoption, Workshop management, Solution Trainings and Disaster management.

02/2021 - 03/2022

TEAM LEAD (SOLUTIONS ARCHITECT) | BUSINESS APPLICATIONS AND SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT UNIT - HA-SHEM LIMITED

CURRENTLY SERVING AS TECHNOLOGY CONSULTANT FOR THE FIRM

- Microsoft Power Platform (Development, Support and Trainings)
- Azure DevOps Engineer (Development, Support and Trainings)
- Microsoft Dynamics 365 CRM (Development, Support and Trainings)
- SharePoint Developer (Development, Support and Trainings)
- Software Engineer.
- Technology Trainer.

Projects include: Azure DevOps infrastructure, Kubernetes, Pipeline Management, Azure Resource and App service management, PR reviews and deployments, Visitor's-Login Application, www.ha-shem.com, www.havis360.com, Sentiment Analyzer App (Using Power Apps, Dataverse and Power Automate), Sentiment Analyzer (using Azure Cognitive services and Microsoft Power Automate), Task Approval Application, Staff Performance and Timesheet Application and Data Recharge Upload App (using Power Apps, Power Automate and SharePoint), SharePoint Intranet and Hybrid Intranet. Power Platform project using Power Platform Solutions (Power BI, Dataverse, Custom connectors, Power Apps, Power Automate, Azure DevOps for Power Platform). I currently contact for the company as a Senior Technology Consultant.

07/2019 - 08/2020

SENIOR SOFTWARE SUPPORT ENGINEER/TECHNICAL LEAD – TEK EXPERTS

- I provide technical support to high level users of Microsoft Dynamics 365, Office 365 and Power Platform products (PowerApps, Flows, Power BI, Microsoft Teams, SharePoint, OneDrive, Outlook 365 for business), Dexterous understanding of Azure Active Directory and Azure DevOps.
 - I analyze and identify bugs with product tools and iterate root cause analysis for case resolutions.
 - I take technical trainings for new engineers and customer employees as demanded on the set technologies been supported

08/2018 - 07/2020

SOFTWARE ARCHITECT, D'ACCUBIN LIMITED

(Technology Strategist, Swiftend)

- Instrumental in the Go Live of an active Identity service (KYC) for both banked and unbanked.
 (www.swiftend.com)
- Co-built various websites and web applications. (<u>www.oibl-nigeria.com</u> www.allifoundation.org, www.twintechservices.com, etc.)
- Cloud and DevOps Management and Engineering.

08/2017 - 07/2018

SAP SOFTWARE CONSULTANT, TWINTECH TECHNICAL SERVICES LIMITED

- Sales and Implementation of SAP SuccessFactors and S4HANA.
- Implementation of SAP PGM (Performance and Goals Management for TSL Logistics)

01/2012 - 07/2015

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER/CREATIVE DESIGNER, ASCENDITECH

- Web and Software Development
- Creative designs (Photoshop, illustrator, and CDR)

EDUCATION

10/2021

MSC MECHANICAL ENGINEERING, UNIVERSITY OF LAGOS

Design and Production Engineering.

10/2015

B.ENG AGRIC & ENVIRONMENTAL ENGINEERING, FEDERAL UNIVERSITY OF

TECHNOLOGY AKURE

SKILLS

- Microsoft Power Platform SME/Consultant,
 Solution Architect, Dynamics CRM, Microsoft
 365, Azure DevOps Expert.
- I have excellent fast and troubleshooting skills
- I have top notch quality analysis skills on CRM and ERP technical investigations.
- Backend development skills with stacks like PHP Laravel, C# ASP.Net and Java and excellent use of MySQL, MsSQL, Microsoft Dataverse, SharePoint Framework and CMS.
- Excellent communication and leadership skills.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Dynamics CRM Implementation - Custodian Group

Lead a team as the Solution Architect/Functional Consultant in the Implementation of Dynamics 365 Customer Service, Marketing and Sales Module, I also deployed Omnichannel for Customer Service and Integrated the Dynamics with the group's core application using plugins and scripting model.

Payment Service Integration with Microsoft Dynamics F & O, Business Central and CRM – SeerBit Lead a team as a Functional Consultant to deploy an AppSource package using X++, AL and C# to build extensions for the various Dynamics service above and created the UI to be deployed on Microsoft AppSource as a deployable package to consume the Backend of the Payment service in question via a developed middleware with nodeJS.

LMS for RCCG SOD

Web Application development for a learning management system. www.rccqsod.com, feastofesther.org, lifebeyondclass.com

Power Apps AWPM Receipts Submission (2020)

Created a Canvas App whose data source is SQL server and it submit it's information to the database. Other related projects that cannot be disclosed for my current employer.

KENL Nigeria Model driven app onboarding App and Microsoft 365 deployment (2019/2020)

Deployed Microsoft 365 for the organization, setting up Microsoft Office, Exchange (mapped to their existing domain/server platform), Teams and SharePoint user for staffs.

Swiftend (2018)

Simplifying Identity verifications across Africa using various API engines for KYC. www.swiftend.com

Alli Foundation (2018)

Full project development and implementation from creation to live deployment. www.allifoundation.org

ACHIEVEMENTS

Omnichannel for Customer Service to Aid prompt response for COVID-19.

Development and Implementation for Omnichannel for customer service for prompt response to COVID-19 Pandemic, Integration of Facebook, WhatsApp and Webchat into the CRM to optimize communication.

Microsoft Office 365 Deployment for KENL Lagos (11/2019)

Deployed Office solutions like Exchange setup, Microsoft Teams and SharePoint.

PowerApps, Power BI and Power Automate Deployment and Training delivered (08/2019 – 11/2019)

- Worked High end users of the above Microsoft product through creating Impactful business automated process using the above product.
- Trained users of Microsoft Teams trainings for an SME Business.
- Trained users in deploying Office 365 solutions for Enterprise optimization.

SAP PGM Implementation (02/2018 – 03/2018)

Sales and Implementation of SAP Performance and Goals Management with training for Company directors.

SUMMER CODE by Incubator (04/2019 – 04/2019)

Trainings for young IT professionals on Web Development, AI, Machine Learning. I personally handled Web App development and Statistics for Machine Learning

CERTIFICATIONS AND AWARDS (05/2016 – Present)

- Microsoft Most Valuable Professional Business Applications 2023
- Creative Designs -- Nurtured Scills (2017) | Google Andela Front End Developer (2018)
- Java Technology, Web, and Data Analytics -- NIIT (2017)
- SAP Design Consultant Solutions (2018)
- Microsoft Office 365, Dynamics CRM, and Power Platform Internal Certifications with Tek Experts.
 (2019 2020)
- MB-910 / PL-900: Microsoft Dynamics and Power Platform fundamentals (2020)
- MB-600: Microsoft Dynamics and Power Platform Solutions Architect (2020)

- PL-100: Microsoft Power Platform App Maker Associate (2021)
- Microsoft Certified Trainer (2021)
- PL-200: Microsoft Power Platform Functional Consultant (2021)
- PL-400: Microsoft Power Platform Developer (2021)

LANGUAGE

English

Full Professional Proficiency

INTERESTS

- Technology implementation, Trainings and Support.
- Innovative Strategies and Development.
- Value sharing and Research.
- Thinking
- Sports, Reading, Movies and Video games.